THOMAS TESFALDET

WEB DEVELOPER

■ thomas.tesfaldet@mail.utoronto.ca soriphen.github.io/thomas-portfolio/ 447-928-4239 Toronto, Canada

in /in/thomas-tesfaldet ? soriphen

SUMMARY

A web developer specializing in the MongoDB, Express, React and Node is stack. A minimalist driven by a design philosophy: light, fast, reliable and style. Passionate in creating applications with eye-catching simplicity, yet robust features. I strive to construct the perfect user experience; succinct and accessible interfaces, intuitive to use on all platforms.

SKILLS

FRONTEND: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Bootstrap 5, Tone.js, p5.js, D3.js, Redux, jQuery, React Native, Chakra UI, SCSS, Pug, styled components, Expo

BACKEND: Node.js, Express, Mongoose, Chai

DATABASE: MongoDB, Firebase **OTHER:** Git. ZenHub. Glide

LANGUAGES: English, Japanese, Tigrinya

EMPLOYMENT

Canada Papers, Shopify Web Store Designer & Developer, 386 Watline Ave, Mississauga, ON L4Z 1X2

June 2021 - Current

- · Assisted in designing the web storefront by creating and organizing product listings.
- · Employed proper SEO practices with product listings resulting in attracting our first customer.
- Translated and transferred CVS files from existing Amazon storefront to the correct Shopify CVS format.
- · Frequently updated product pricing and inventory to accurately reflect those sold at physical storefront

Consoul, Junior React Native Developer, Toronto, ON

Jan. 2022 - Current

- Designed and implemented authentication module with firebase integration for both iOS and Android apps.
- Contributed to architectural design decisions and implemented said designs (custom drawer, redux implementation, etc.) to apps, as well as participating and collaborating in feature discovery discussions with team.
- Core developer for working on MVP -- responsible for setting goals for deliverables and achieving them.
- Collaborated with co-developer with weekly code-alonas.
- Described processes/updates in layman terms for management as well as in technical terms for co-developer during weekly meetings.

PROJECTS

Drum Step Sequencer
Using React, tone is, and p5 is, developed a 16 step sequencer with an audio visualizer and sounds created from a digital audio workstation.

June 2021 - Aug. 2021

- · The user would click on boxes which would store audio in a multidimensional array to be played through integration of tone.js.
- The user would be able to select which aroup of samples to play for any row, preserving sample placement from previous selection.
- Added the ability to add/remove rows for additional samples to be played.
- Integrated tone is with React and p5 is to create a seamless interaction where waveform data extracted by tone is passed by React to be drawn by p5 is in real-time to create an audio visualizer reactive to outputted sound.

May 2021 - June 2021

Using React, created a responsive markdown previewer integrated with Ace Editor.

- Developed a mobile-responsive input/output markdown processor with live-preview functionality.
- Successfully integrated JavaScript libraries highlight, is with marked, is to be used within react-ace in order to properly convert a written code-block in markdown to JavaScript syntax highlighting.
- Integrated react-ace in order to implement the functionality and design of modern code editors with features such as: gutters, line numbering, markdown syntax highlighting, active line highlighting, and folding

Student Profile Search Sept. 2021 - Sept. 2021

Using React, designed and developed a mobile-responsive search filter using a mock list of student profiles fetched from an API endpoint.

- Implemented a tag feature that allows a user to create as many of their own removable tags and attach them to a student profile for search filtering.
- Developed a search name feature that filters by a student's first name, or last name, or both through regex.

 Produced the state of the state o
- Developed a search tag feature that filters through created tags and can be used for search filtering in combination with the search name bar.

URL Shortener Microservice

Oct. 2021 - Oct. 2021

- - Implemented the validator, is library for validating inputted URLs, otherwise returning a JSON with proper error messaging.
 - Integrated with MongoDB to produce a real-time updating database for storage of short URL values
 - Using Mongoose, implemented an increment feature where each subsequent short value in the database is increased so as to give each new document a unique short URL

EDUCATION

freeCodeCamp

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification 2021 Back End Development and APIs Certification 2021 https://www.freecodecamp.org/soriphen

Juno College

Web Development Course 2020

University of Toronto

Bachelor of Arts (Honours) East Asian Studies 2019

Kwansei Gakuin University
Participant in the Global Career Seminar -- worked with Orix Corporation and Japanese peers to solve an industry problem and deliver a presentation of my findings in a formal Japanese setting

July 2018 - Aug. 2018 Sept. 2016 - Sept. 2017

Akita International University